# Noe Misael Nieto Arroyo

I have a bachelor's degree in Electronics Engineering and I expect to earn a Master's degree in engineering by June 2018. As Engineer I've worked with data acquisition and idustrial instrumentation. Then I pursued a career as Software Engineering working as SysAdmin, backend & frontend developer, and DBA. During the last 10+ years I've been working almost exclusively with FLOSS software such as Linux, Python, Django, JavaScript, jQuery, PHP, PostgreSQL, MySql and SQLite, among others, but I also know my way around the Windows/SQL Server/ASP.net stack.

In my spare time I take care of some of my side projects. Also, I enjoy teching Python to whoever is interested.

### **Education**

- June 2018; Master's degree in Engineering, UABC Mexicali. Estudio experimental y vía simulación de los materiales para celdas solares de tercera generación.
- September 2006; Arizona State University; Data Acquisition training seminar by JACMET group.
- September 2012; Electronics Engineering, Instituto Tecnológico de Puebla.
- June 2000; Computer Programmer technician diploma, Universidad Popular Autónoma del Estado de Puebla.

# Work Experience

 Social Reality - Sysadmin, DBA, backend developer. 2015 ~ 2016.

Working wit Linux, Apache, MySQL, PHP, Python, Puppet, Vagrant under high pressure.

• Valutech Outsourcing S.A. de C.V. Sysadmin/DBA. 2013 ~ 2015. Worked

in the datacenter with regular tasks ofmaintenance, backup and performace troubleshoting Windows Server, Linux and SQL Server.

• NNieto Consulting Services - Freelancer

- This used to be my main business; Now it's only part time. But eventually I might come back to freelancing.
- I started it on April 2011. I provided software development services and training. I worked with different companies and intsitutions in Mexico and Argentina.
  - Homeviva, an Argentinian startup in the construction industry. My role here is as a full stack developer. Key technologies: Linux, nginx, Python, Grok (first iterations of the project), Pyramid, PostgreSQL, JSON and AngularJS. I've been working for them since August 2011. Website: http://www.homeviva.com.ar
  - Centro de Psiquiatría y Psicología Holokinética (CPH). CPH is based in Mexicali, Baja California, Mexico. It is a non-profit organization that promotes Holokinetic Psychology and Unitary Perception. I've been helping them to build their E-commerce site for books, audios and DVD's. Key technologies: Linux, Plone (First version of the site), Django (a new version of the site, due in June 2013), PayPal. I've been working with them since March 2010. Website:

http://www.holokinesislibros.com/

• Venddo, a Mexican Startup based in Mexico City. They analyze information in social networks to identify profiles of potential customers. I've been working for as a backend developer since March 2013. *Key technologies*: Python, SQLAlchemy, twitter API. *Website*: http://venddo.com/

- AlfaOmega Grupo Editor. AlfaOmega is one of the biggest publishers of technical books in Latin America. They have offices in Mexico City, Colombia, Argentina and Spain. I worked with them to port their e-learning platform from Plone 3 to Plone 4. I also gave them Plone development training courses for their in-site developers. From March 2011 until May 2012. Website: http://libroweb.alfaomega.com.mx/
- Universidad Pedagógica Nacional. Plone migration consultant. May 2011. Website: http://www.upn.mx/
- WAM Ready2Fill. Based on Oaxaca, Mexico, Ready2Fill develops business solutions with free software. I wrote a Python training course for their team of engineers so they could start

developing their solutions with Django and Python. October 2011. Website: http://Ready2Fill.com/

- Insignia Diseño. Design agency from San Luis Potosí, México. I developed their portfolio gallery. Key technologies: CakePHP, jQuery, jQueryTools. Website: http://insigniadiseno.com/portafolio/
- iServices de México Web/Python developer
  - In charge of integration/development and maintenance of their in-house LCMS systems. My activities involved Linux System administration, project management, Web Software development, Software engineering and maintenance with the Plone CMS and emergency assistance in case of software failure.
  - Time span: January 2009 until April 2011.
  - · Location: Puebla and Mexico City.
- Honeywell Aerospace de Mexico Data Acquisition Engineer
  - As a Data Acquisition Engineer I was in charge of the commissioning and operation of hardware and software. I also played a developer role for in-house software tools. Also, I was specialist in pressure, temperature, voltage, current

- and vibration measurements as well as video over IP and networking. Our team was also in charge of assuring that our instruments were always calibrated with traceability to the NIST and always ready for use, that included dealing with purchasing and supply chain departments.
- Wide experience in Video Over IP and Networking as a result of intern projects.
- Time span: From May 2006 until December 2008
- Location: Mexicali, Phoenix.
- Gameloft S de RL Multiplayer programmer
  - Implement test and deploy modifications of the multiplayer server (written in C++) and multiplayer API used in networked games for mobile phones.
  - Implement, test and deploy modifications needed to support specific models of cellphones by the different game titles published by Gameloft.
  - Time span: February to May, 2006.
  - · Location: Mexicali.
- Centro de ingenieria Instituto Nacional de Astrofísica Óptica y Electrónica - Internship. Embedded systems laboratory assistant
  - Work related to data acquisition, real time, tracking and control systems.
  - Time span: 2006.

• Location: Tonanzintla (Puebla).

#### • FreeLance IT Consultant

• Basic computer training and computer technician. Installation of voice and data networks, independent software developer.

• Time span: 2000 - 2005

• Location: Puebla.

### **Skills**

• Electronics Engineering

I used to be a hardware guy. I did fun stuff with data acquisition systems (Voltage, Current, Pressure, Fuel flow, and Vibration) and some expensive toys from these manufacturers: Dewetron/Dewesoft, Scanivalve, LEM, B&K, Ectron and Ametek, NI PXI, LDS Genesis.

## Training and Conferences

- X Jornada Académica, Social y Deportiva 2012 - Nov. 12th-16th, Instituto Tecnológico de Oaxaca, Mexico
  - 20 hour python course for students of Software Engineering.
- Seminario de Aplicaciones de las Tecnologías de la Información y Comunicaciones - Sept. 3rd-7th, Instituto Tecnológico de Puebla, Mexico
  - Speaker. One 45 minute talk about basic multimedia applications with GStreamer.
  - Trainner. Five-hour Python course for newcomers. Attendants included students and teachers of the IT Academia of the ITP.
- PyCON US 2012 March 7th-15th, Santa Clara, CA.
  - Conference attendant and sprinter.

• Attended to the tutorial DevOps for Python: Doing More With Less

https://us.pycon.org/2012/schedule/presentation/28

- FLISOL 2011 April 9th, Puebla, Puebla
  - Speaker. I talked a bit about the GStreamer Framework.
- PyCON US 2011 March 9th-17th, Atlanta, GA.
  - · Conference attendant and sprinter.
- PyCON US 2010 March, Atlanta, GA.
  - · Conference attendant and sprinter.
- PyCON US 2009 March, Chicago, IL.
  - · Conference attendant and sprinter.